<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MakerGirl</title>
    <description>MakerGirl is a program led by University of Illinois students that educates 7-10 year old girls on STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, Mathematics) fields through 3-D printing workshops at the College of Business MakerLab, creative activities, and lessons on leading women in STEM fields.</description>
    <link>http://makergirl.us//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://makergirl.us//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 18:41:08 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 18:41:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of STEM Education During Your Childhood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/04/stemwomen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Importance of STEM Education During Your Childhood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second Semester Senior. It feels incredibly abnormal as I typed the previous phrase, because it’s surreal that in less than six weeks, I’ll no longer be a student. As much as I’m ready to stop taking exams, I’m anxious to leave a place that shaped my professional and personal identities. While I always thought that my second semester I’d be cruising through school and focusing on social interactions, I made the decision to become involved with a nonprofit startup on campus called MakerGirl, and it’s definitely impacted my life for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first heard that MakerGirl promotes Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics (STEM) education across girls aged 7-10 by teaching them how to 3D print, the nerd inside of me was thrilled. I loved playing with Legos and 3D puzzles as a child, and vividly remember upset for a solid 10 minutes when my aunt and uncle gifted me a purse instead of my usual gift, a fresh box of Legos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/04/legos.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Importance of STEM Education During Your Childhood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew older and mingled with various classmates whose backgrounds were different than mine, I realized how these simple gifts were more of a privilege than a normalcy. I’ve met amazingly bright and intelligent female friends who’ve jokingly stated that their moms curbed their exposure to STEM fields and opportunities because their mom thought “it was too difficult for me” or “it would stress me out too much”. While they chuckled a little after that and moved on to a new conversation after, I couldn’t help but internally dwell on it and think to myself, “What’s so difficult about STEM, and what on Earth could you possibly be lacking you’re deemed incapable of studying STEM”? MakerGirl has further widened my perspective, and taught me that there circumstances that discourage female involvement in STEM even more; from a lack of resources and opportunities to girls shying away at young ages despite being interested because of the abundance of males in the classroom or workshop and them feeling uncomfortable. Shockingly, the gender disparity has been growing since the 80s, when it was at its lowest. As a society, we’ve moved forward through technology, and innovation, but we forgot to make females a part of that journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am an ambitious, successful, driven and passionate individual today because I was told from a young age that I am unstoppable force, and that with the right mindset and work ethic I can achieve anything. That stemmed from being exposed to toys and gadgets that encouraged my academic development and problem solving skills. My childhood made me cognizant that even the smallest actions can result in the largest impact. Through MakerGirl, I’m applying this realization and building the STEM foundations of girls today who will help build the future of the USA tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/04/12/importance-of-stem-in-childhood/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/04/12/importance-of-stem-in-childhood/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Spirit of Entrepreneurship in Rural America</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/04/FabLab2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FabLab1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over spring break Alyssa and I represented MakerGirl at the Fab Lab Symposium in Bentonville, Arkansas. The symposium brought together Fab Labs from across the country for three days of discussion centered on entrepreneurship and innovation. A majority of the labs in attendance were from rural areas and they shared with us how entrepreneurship and innovation are changing the shape of their communities and economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common theme we heard from labs in rural areas was they have trouble keeping their graduating high school seniors in the area because the students don’t see a future for themselves in their rural community. This is hard on the community because it stunts economic growth. The Fab Labs are working hard to solve this problem by emphasizing STEM in schools at every age. Many Fab Labs are located in high schools and community colleges, which provides accessibility to the teachers and students. Teachers have begun to incorporate trips to the labs in their curriculum in order to build their students’ creativity and technical skills. By emphasizing creativity and building within the community at a young age, the labs hope to see their young entrepreneurs stay in the area, start new businesses and help the economy grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/04/FabLab1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FabLab1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common theme was mass job losses. Within the past decade, many communities in the Appalachia region of the country have been hit with significant job losses due to mining, steel, and paper companies shutting down. With some communities having lost almost 85% of their jobs, they have turned to entrepreneurship and innovation to rebuild their economy. The Fab Labs in these areas have been a very important part of this process because they provide a space where people can go to learn new skills and exercise their creativity. Community colleges have also played an important role and have begun creating entrepreneurial programs that encourage students to start their own small businesses in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of rural communities are located in close proximity to each other their community lines begin to blur as they grow. This growth process is occurring in Northwest Arkansas, a region comprised of Fayetteville, Bentonville, Rogers, and Springdale. Northwest Arkansas, home to Wal-Mart and Tyson, is a fast growing region that is using entrepreneurship and innovation to bring a sense of unity to the four towns in their region. They are working to create an innovation center; a part of town intended to showcase new businesses. They provide different financial incentives to businesses looking to move to the area and to individuals looking to create new businesses. The region also hosts a variety of different maker-themed events and contests to celebrate the entrepreneurs in their region. Their entrepreneurial efforts are intended to benefit the region as a whole, as opposed to the individual towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning about the entrepreneurial spirit of rural America was fascinating and exciting to me. After three days of the symposium, it was clear to me that this trend is not focused on one region of the country, the entrepreneurial spirit is truly beginning to blossom in rural communities across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/04/08/entrepreneural-spirit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/04/08/entrepreneural-spirit/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Letter to the President</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr. President,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a freshman working towards a degree in Materials Science and Engineering at the University of Illinois. As a woman in engineering, I have faced criticism, derogatory comments, and negative stereotypes from my male peers and teachers. During one occasion, a classmate told me that my opinion meant nothing and that I belonged in a kitchen. At first, these comments tore me apart and dragged me down. I would spend hours crying in the bathroom at school asking myself why I even attempted to do something that apparently, I was not meant to do. Unfortunately, Mr. President, this occurs to a majority of girls pursuing STEM fields across the United States. Most are dragged down and belittled to the point where they cannot go on, and resort to something “easier”. I am happy to say that upon coming to college, my outlook has changed. I have realized that I am pursuing engineering for a reason. I want to make the world a better place. I am fueled to push forward because I know I must. I must encourage young girls to become involved in STEM because as a country, we need women in STEM. As the president of the United States, you should support this issue because increasing the amount of women in STEM will increase the amount of solutions to the problems we face in our country today. We must support and encourage women in engineering to the fullest because without them, we are only half as productive of a country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am striving towards gender equality by introducing young girls to 3-D printing in a start-up (501c3) nonprofit organization, MakerGirl. In MakerGirl, we inspire girls to live and dream as unstoppable forces that say yes to the challenges of the future. We encourage them by teaching them about innovative companies, women leaders, and new technology. In our sessions, girls get to implement their creativity through a hands-on 3-D printing design process. This summer, in order to reach girls in rural areas without access to STEM education, we are taking our sessions mobile! We have reached over 60% of our Kickstarter goal but need all of the support we can get in order for our dream to become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the President of the United States, I know you are probably extremely busy with issues deemed more imperative. But I am urging you to support our efforts. Currently STEM fields are comprised of only 24% women. Supporting women in STEM is one of the most promising investments you can make as President.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/president-reply.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PresidentLetter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/03/30/letter-to-the-president/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/03/30/letter-to-the-president/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Off Road Vehicles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/car.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Off Road Vehicles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always loved cars. My dad would quiz five years old me on long road trips on the model of the cars that would pass by giving me his fatherly goofy smile when I would get them right. I was the type of kid that played with Hot Wheels instead of dolls and tried to fix old remote control racecars for fun. Therefore when I got to college being in a club that got to actually build cars was a dream come true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember it was Quad Day freshmen year and I was trying to evade the hordes of people while looking around for a club that would catch my eye. There were a couple but nothing that had me bouncing with excitement, that is until I used a different sense, my hearing. Out of nowhere, a load roar propagated through the Quad, a low revving growling noise that caused a slight tremble in the grass I was standing on. I knew that noise belonged to an engine that was built for speed. I immediately left the booth I was standing by and rushed in the direction of the commotion. When I got there not only did I see the formula car from which the roar was coming from but also a whole alley filled with clubs that had built their own vehicles ranging from those of speed to power. I was home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking around there was the formula electric team, another that raced mini tractors, and one that even built car like machines that tried to bulldoze each other over. All of them interested me but then I glanced over to the corner of the alley where a metal bar contraption with wheels was sitting. Heading over towards that car, I noticed the large wheels, the amount of suspension shocks, and the large sign next to it that said “Off-Road”. I walked up to the members of the BAJA SAE club and asked them what they did. They replied, “We design and build our own off-road vehicle and then race them through the mud and muck to beat Michigan”. Once I heard that I knew I had to be a part of this team. I am all for speed and elegance but there is something about being in forests and swamps trying to conquer the natural landscape that has always appealed to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/grainger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Off Road Vehicles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last three years of being on the BAJA team, I have worked on various parts of the cars and have even gotten to drive them. Being able to design parts of the suspension and actually manufacturing and mounting it myself onto the car has been an amazing experience and I have learned so much from being on the team. Even now as I write this, I am working on finalizing our steering in which I am designing the entire steering mechanism using the rack and pinion technic, trying to lower our steering ratio to give us tighter, quicker turns on the track. It’s sometimes frustrating work especially when creating CAD designs on Creo and often there are times I want to chuck the entire computer out the fourth floor window of Grainger Library, but I keep doing it because I am passionate about the subject. It is the old love/hate relationship that keeps me pushing through because in the end when everything is said and done, there is an off-road vehicle that has parts that I have envisioned and created, has part of me essentially. That feeling of accomplishment and success is what makes it all worth it and is why I became a part of the BAJA team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/03/22/offroad-vehicles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/03/22/offroad-vehicles/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How MakerGirl can change the Champaign area for the upcoming generation of kids growing up in the area</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC05800.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Making Change&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in the Champaign-Urbana area, I wasn’t necessary always encouraged to explore the STEM field. Especially coming from a family where higher education wasn’t a common factor between generations, the STEM field wasn’t something my parents felt I needed to be a part of, thus, they never had the need to seek out opportunities for me as a young girl. In school, the word “innovation” wasn’t clearly defined for me or many of my female classmates. When I looked around at my classmates who were actively pursuing their interests within the STEM field, it was primarily boys with a few girls sprinkled into the mix. Regardless, both groups were introduced to the STEM field through parental influence, rather than through the education available in the schools. Therefore, it is so vital to have organizations such as MakerGirl be embedded into the Champaign-Urbana community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Champaign-Urbana is a unique area that encompasses various types of families. Being located in central Illinois along with having the University of Illinois in the background, the Champaign-Urbana area has the opportunity to be progressive in terms of promoting STEM education for children within the community. Compared to the rest of Illinois, Champaign – Urbana is considered as quite diverse, with the percentage of minorities often exceeding Illinois’s makeup for the state’s population. With such as diverse population, organizations that introduce and foster the interest for STEM fields, such as MakerGirl, has limitless opportunities to create a lasting impact for the generations of children who do not have the chance to understand or apply their interest in STEM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC06259.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Making Change&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MakerGirl can promote STEM into a child’s life in a way that not all educators or parental figures can as MakerGirl focuses on the fun behind STEM through the use of 3D printing. It allows participates to create something from their own imagination right on the spot. MakerGirl allows upcoming generations of kids in the Champaign-Urbana community to be exposed to the innovative world of STEM through design, discussion, and creation, regardless of what their pervious knowledge of STEM was. With more and more organizations like MakerGirl, the gap of who represents the STEM field will close. Not only will more females be encouraged to seek out opportunities in STEM but there will also be more diversity in terms of race and socioeconomic backgrounds, especially in Champaign-Urbana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MakerGirl makes it possible for kids who will become first generation college students to begin thinking about a career in STEM long before they even step foot in a lecture hall. Opportunities in STEM will no longer to be limited to a certain stereotype and as more investment is expanded to a more diverse younger generation, there will be continuous interest in STEM. MakerGirl will help change the faces of STEM starting with kids within the Champaign-Urbana area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/03/10/making-change/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/03/10/making-change/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stereotypes of Girls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC04922.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stereotypes of Girls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Girl Scouts of America, only 13% of teenage girls say that their first career choice is a STEM career.  Unfortunately in this day and age, women of all ages fall victim to many stereotypes which can affect them for the rest of their lives.  Women are put in to a mold.  Starting from a young age, girls see what types of jobs and activities are meant for women.  This is the main problem, there are no activities we should limit ourselves to.  Women can do any activity and can perform any task they would like.  We should not disregard something we want to do just because we were taught it was not meant for women or that it does not fit into the stereotypical mold of a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One large stereotype these young girls are facing is that they are meant to be a homemaker and mother.  The media portrays girls as always playing with baby dolls or playing with cosmetic items.  Boys are portrayed by playing with building blocks and tools.  From the start, girls see that they are limited to these toys and some very important learning tools.  Girls are often also given toys like a kitchen set or tea set to play with, while boys are given a set of tools or trucks.  This enforces even to these young kids what their roles are.  Girls are shown they are supposed to cook and clean while men do hard work.  Young girls then limit their options for their futures based off of this stereotype.  This leads to the statistic above, that only 13% of teen women want to be a part of a STEM career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC00266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stereotypes of Girls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls also face the stereotype that they are fragile and weak.  Women are portrayed as skinny and delicate while men are strong and muscular.  Girls are ballerinas and teachers and cooks, while men are football players and construction workers.  Girls are not shown they can be strong and that they can make big differences.  Young kids are taught about great men and women in our current and past history, but these stereotypes always linger.  At a young age, girls then start quitting sports they think are for boys only and do not participate in activities they feel are meant for boys.  These stereotypes are affecting girls and how they choose to live the rest of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC00260.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stereotypes of Girls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They way to reverse how young women see these stereotypes is not to try and eliminate them, but to instead prove them wrong.  Girls should be encouraged to do activities and tasks they see as for boys only.  They should be shown that they can make amazing things with building blocks and that they can be just as strong as the young men around them.  They need to be given tools to play with instead or another baby doll.  These girls learn from how others act around them, so it is the job of parents and teachers to help breakdown those stereotypes.  Without those limitations, girls can finally grow up to see their great potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/03/01/stereotypes-of-girls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/03/01/stereotypes-of-girls/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>REACT Program</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chemistry.illinois.edu/outreach/react/&quot;&gt;REACT program&lt;/a&gt; is a student run organization that visits local elementary schools and introduces the students to hands-on chemistry activities. I have participated in the REACT program for the past three years because I think introducing chemistry to kids at a young age helps reduce their apprehension towards the often-difficult subject in the future.
At the beginning of the visit, we ask the kids if they know the definition of chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/chemistry1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;REACT program&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are always very eager to answer and their responses are often impressive. The kids then split up into small groups and work through a series of experiments. My favorite visit was a forensic-themed visit. The kids were presented with a mystery and they had to use common forensic techniques to find Zippy the stolen turtle. They used fingerprinting and basic chromatography to narrow down a list of suspects. Watching them put on their chemistry goggles and rubber gloves is adorable but also powerful because it allows them to assume the role of a scientist. They were very eager to help solve the mystery and asked very good questions along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the small group experiments are finished, we do a series of demonstrations for the whole class. The most popular demonstration is the bottle rocket. The demo involves a two-liter soda bottle that is filled with vinegar. A tissue filled with baking soda is dropped into the bottle and the bottle is sealed with a cork. As the pressure inside the bottle builds up, the cork flies across the room with a loud pop. The reaction from the kids is priceless. Some of them cover their ears, some of them sit there with wide eyes, and many of them gasp in amazement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/chemistry2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;REACT program&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The REACT program has been one of my favorite parts of my time at Illinois and I would definitely recommend getting involved in it if you love working with kids!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/02/23/chemistry-react-program/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/02/23/chemistry-react-program/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Representation of Women in Gaming Culture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My parents bought me my first video game system when I was five, and it was a Nintendo 64. This was the start of my interest in video games, specifically console games, but I didn’t really get into them until I started playing PC (computer) games when I was 17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To name a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minecraft- Independent/Sandbox game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Minecraft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guild Wars 2- Massively Multiplayer Online Role-playing Game (MMORPG)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guildwars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearthstone- Strategy card game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hearthstone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;League of Legends- Multiplayer Online Battle Arena (MOBA)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image4.png&quot; alt=&quot;League&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Counterstrike – First Person Shooter (FPS)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Counterstrike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, I like to try different games with my friends, but these are the ones I play on a regular basis. Although the genres of all these games are significantly different most of their communities have something in common: A disproportionate number of males to females. While the number of female players to male players can change depending on the game, there is still an underrepresentation. This is largely due to the gaming industry in general catering their advertising to boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am online I am almost always on some type of voice chat like Skype. In my own personal experience, I am sometimes the only girl or one of two girls that are playing the game or in the voice chat. This has been consistently true for every chat and friend group I have joined. If you do a quick google search many statistics will come up showing that women make up 48%-52% of “gamers.” Personally, I do not agree with this statistic. After looking into the types of video games the polls consisted of, mobile games like Candy Crush and Trivia Crack are always included in these stats. Another example of this is a game like Farmville on Facebook. While these are technically a type of video game, people that play these games are not usually a part of what most gamers consider gaming culture. If I were to take a guess at the percentage of female to male gamers based on what I think a gamer is, I would say it is closer to 40-60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the overwhelming perception is that “girl gamers” tend to be few and far between, which is something that will hopefully change with time. Since this is the perception of the gaming demographic the gaming industry will continue to cater to men. This is apparent in the objectification and sexualization of female characters in games. Unfortunately, this also translates to girl gamers in real life as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;asdasds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is becoming increasingly popular to “stream” a video game. Streaming is when someone shares an online video in real time of them playing the video game. They will often have a webcam on them while they play the game as well; a very popular streamer known as Kaceytron often dresses provocatively in order to get more viewers for her channel. Is she an accurate representation of most girl gamers? No, but she is playing into how women are objectified in video games in order to make money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image7.png&quot; alt=&quot;asdasds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that in order for the demographic in gaming culture to change, the stereotype that video games are for boys needs to change. If this changes the industry may start to change their target audience to include all genders instead of just catering to one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/02/16/representation-of-women-in-gaming-culture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/02/16/representation-of-women-in-gaming-culture/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
