<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MakerGirl</title>
    <description>MakerGirl is a program led by University of Illinois students that educates 7-10 year old girls on STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, Mathematics) fields through 3-D printing workshops at the College of Business MakerLab, creative activities, and lessons on leading women in STEM fields.</description>
    <link>http://makergirl.us//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://makergirl.us//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 09:30:28 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 09:30:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How MakerGirl can change the Champaign area for the upcoming generation of kids growing up in the area</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing up in the Champaign-Urbana area, I wasn’t necessary always encouraged to explore the STEM field. Especially coming from a family where higher education wasn’t a common factor between generations, the STEM field wasn’t something my parents felt I needed to be a part of, thus, they never had the need to seek out opportunities for me as a young girl. In school, the word “innovation” wasn’t clearly defined for me or many of my female classmates. When I looked around at my classmates who were actively pursuing their interests within the STEM field, it was primarily boys with a few girls sprinkled into the mix. Regardless, both groups were introduced to the STEM field through parental influence, rather than through the education available in the schools. Therefore, it is so vital to have organizations such as MakerGirl be embedded into the Champaign-Urbana community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Champaign-Urbana is a unique area that encompasses various types of families. Being located in central Illinois along with having the University of Illinois in the background, the Champaign-Urbana area has the opportunity to be progressive in terms of promoting STEM education for children within the community. Compared to the rest of Illinois, Champaign – Urbana is considered as quite diverse, with the percentage of minorities often exceeding Illinois’s makeup for the state’s population. With such as diverse population, organizations that introduce and foster the interest for STEM fields, such as MakerGirl, has limitless opportunities to create a lasting impact for the generations of children who do not have the chance to understand or apply their interest in STEM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MakerGirl can promote STEM into a child’s life in a way that not all educators or parental figures can as MakerGirl focuses on the fun behind STEM through the use of 3D printing. It allows participates to create something from their own imagination right on the spot. MakerGirl allows upcoming generations of kids in the Champaign-Urbana community to be exposed to the innovative world of STEM through design, discussion, and creation, regardless of what their pervious knowledge of STEM was. With more and more organizations like MakerGirl, the gap of who represents the STEM field will close. Not only will more females be encouraged to seek out opportunities in STEM but there will also be more diversity in terms of race and socioeconomic backgrounds, especially in Champaign-Urbana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MakerGirl makes it possible for kids who will become first generation college students to begin thinking about a career in STEM long before they even step foot in a lecture hall. Opportunities in STEM will no longer to be limited to a certain stereotype and as more investment is expanded to a more diverse younger generation, there will be continuous interest in STEM. MakerGirl will help change the faces of STEM starting with kids within the Champaign-Urbana area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/03/05/making-change/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/03/05/making-change/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stereotypes of Girls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC04922.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stereotypes of Girls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Girl Scouts of America, only 13% of teenage girls say that their first career choice is a STEM career.  Unfortunately in this day and age, women of all ages fall victim to many stereotypes which can affect them for the rest of their lives.  Women are put in to a mold.  Starting from a young age, girls see what types of jobs and activities are meant for women.  This is the main problem, there are no activities we should limit ourselves to.  Women can do any activity and can perform any task they would like.  We should not disregard something we want to do just because we were taught it was not meant for women or that it does not fit into the stereotypical mold of a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One large stereotype these young girls are facing is that they are meant to be a homemaker and mother.  The media portrays girls as always playing with baby dolls or playing with cosmetic items.  Boys are portrayed by playing with building blocks and tools.  From the start, girls see that they are limited to these toys and some very important learning tools.  Girls are often also given toys like a kitchen set or tea set to play with, while boys are given a set of tools or trucks.  This enforces even to these young kids what their roles are.  Girls are shown they are supposed to cook and clean while men do hard work.  Young girls then limit their options for their futures based off of this stereotype.  This leads to the statistic above, that only 13% of teen women want to be a part of a STEM career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC00266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stereotypes of Girls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls also face the stereotype that they are fragile and weak.  Women are portrayed as skinny and delicate while men are strong and muscular.  Girls are ballerinas and teachers and cooks, while men are football players and construction workers.  Girls are not shown they can be strong and that they can make big differences.  Young kids are taught about great men and women in our current and past history, but these stereotypes always linger.  At a young age, girls then start quitting sports they think are for boys only and do not participate in activities they feel are meant for boys.  These stereotypes are affecting girls and how they choose to live the rest of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/03/DSC00260.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stereotypes of Girls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They way to reverse how young women see these stereotypes is not to try and eliminate them, but to instead prove them wrong.  Girls should be encouraged to do activities and tasks they see as for boys only.  They should be shown that they can make amazing things with building blocks and that they can be just as strong as the young men around them.  They need to be given tools to play with instead or another baby doll.  These girls learn from how others act around them, so it is the job of parents and teachers to help breakdown those stereotypes.  Without those limitations, girls can finally grow up to see their great potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/03/01/stereotypes-of-girls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/03/01/stereotypes-of-girls/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>REACT Program</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chemistry.illinois.edu/outreach/react/&quot;&gt;REACT program&lt;/a&gt; is a student run organization that visits local elementary schools and introduces the students to hands-on chemistry activities. I have participated in the REACT program for the past three years because I think introducing chemistry to kids at a young age helps reduce their apprehension towards the often-difficult subject in the future.
At the beginning of the visit, we ask the kids if they know the definition of chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/chemistry1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;REACT program&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are always very eager to answer and their responses are often impressive. The kids then split up into small groups and work through a series of experiments. My favorite visit was a forensic-themed visit. The kids were presented with a mystery and they had to use common forensic techniques to find Zippy the stolen turtle. They used fingerprinting and basic chromatography to narrow down a list of suspects. Watching them put on their chemistry goggles and rubber gloves is adorable but also powerful because it allows them to assume the role of a scientist. They were very eager to help solve the mystery and asked very good questions along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the small group experiments are finished, we do a series of demonstrations for the whole class. The most popular demonstration is the bottle rocket. The demo involves a two-liter soda bottle that is filled with vinegar. A tissue filled with baking soda is dropped into the bottle and the bottle is sealed with a cork. As the pressure inside the bottle builds up, the cork flies across the room with a loud pop. The reaction from the kids is priceless. Some of them cover their ears, some of them sit there with wide eyes, and many of them gasp in amazement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/chemistry2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;REACT program&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The REACT program has been one of my favorite parts of my time at Illinois and I would definitely recommend getting involved in it if you love working with kids!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/02/23/chemistry-react-program/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/02/23/chemistry-react-program/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Representation of Women in Gaming Culture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My parents bought me my first video game system when I was five, and it was a Nintendo 64. This was the start of my interest in video games, specifically console games, but I didn’t really get into them until I started playing PC (computer) games when I was 17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To name a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minecraft- Independent/Sandbox game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Minecraft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guild Wars 2- Massively Multiplayer Online Role-playing Game (MMORPG)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guildwars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearthstone- Strategy card game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hearthstone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;League of Legends- Multiplayer Online Battle Arena (MOBA)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image4.png&quot; alt=&quot;League&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Counterstrike – First Person Shooter (FPS)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Counterstrike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, I like to try different games with my friends, but these are the ones I play on a regular basis. Although the genres of all these games are significantly different most of their communities have something in common: A disproportionate number of males to females. While the number of female players to male players can change depending on the game, there is still an underrepresentation. This is largely due to the gaming industry in general catering their advertising to boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am online I am almost always on some type of voice chat like Skype. In my own personal experience, I am sometimes the only girl or one of two girls that are playing the game or in the voice chat. This has been consistently true for every chat and friend group I have joined. If you do a quick google search many statistics will come up showing that women make up 48%-52% of “gamers.” Personally, I do not agree with this statistic. After looking into the types of video games the polls consisted of, mobile games like Candy Crush and Trivia Crack are always included in these stats. Another example of this is a game like Farmville on Facebook. While these are technically a type of video game, people that play these games are not usually a part of what most gamers consider gaming culture. If I were to take a guess at the percentage of female to male gamers based on what I think a gamer is, I would say it is closer to 40-60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the overwhelming perception is that “girl gamers” tend to be few and far between, which is something that will hopefully change with time. Since this is the perception of the gaming demographic the gaming industry will continue to cater to men. This is apparent in the objectification and sexualization of female characters in games. Unfortunately, this also translates to girl gamers in real life as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;asdasds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is becoming increasingly popular to “stream” a video game. Streaming is when someone shares an online video in real time of them playing the video game. They will often have a webcam on them while they play the game as well; a very popular streamer known as Kaceytron often dresses provocatively in order to get more viewers for her channel. Is she an accurate representation of most girl gamers? No, but she is playing into how women are objectified in video games in order to make money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2016/02/image7.png&quot; alt=&quot;asdasds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that in order for the demographic in gaming culture to change, the stereotype that video games are for boys needs to change. If this changes the industry may start to change their target audience to include all genders instead of just catering to one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://makergirl.us//2016/02/16/representation-of-women-in-gaming-culture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://makergirl.us//2016/02/16/representation-of-women-in-gaming-culture/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
